Video bridges the gap between survivors and audiences
between seeing and changing.
At WITNESS the purpose of video is to get the story told
the right people to see it and action taken.
WITNESS has been empowering women around the world for 17 years
partnering with organizations and working on issues impacting women and girls.
From exposing the trafficking of women in eastern Europe
to advocating for women landmine victims in Senegal
to protecting our elderly from abuse, right here in the United States...
WITNESS changes lives.
Women who have survived human rights abuses are speaking up
so that others won't experience the same injustices.
Violence against women in Zimbabwe is because
women are becoming more and more involved in politics.
To try and to stop these women from involvement in politics
they are beaten, they are sexually assaulted.
RAU decided to work with WITNESS
because it will give people a chance to watch the film
and then to see what is going on in Zimbabwe.
In Yemen, witnesses working with the Sisters Arab Forum
to advocate for the rights of minority "Akhdam" women
The video was screened in Yemen to members
of Parliament, journalists and civil society
and has unfortunately since been banned.
WITNESS is working to have the ban lifted.
In Mexico, DUAL INJUSTICE tells the story of 19-year old Neyra
who disappeared on her way home from school in 2003.
WITNESS recently met the mexican president and select government officials.
They have since created a working group
to end the disappearances and murders that have
claimed the lives of over 450 girls and young women.
In Macedonia, our WITNESS partner advocates
to end violence and discrimination against women
including sex workers.
Violence and discrimination against women and girls
is one of today's most pervasive human rights violations.
WITNESS empowers those standing up for the rights of women
to expose injustices, tell their stories
and create lasting change.